# Néda EL HADJ-MIMOUNE

# Technical Writer



## CONTACT



+33 07 85 53 65 44



neda.ryanne2@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/néda-mimoune

## **EDUCATION**

2020-2022

#### Université Paris Cité (Paris Diderot)

Master in Multilingual technical communication Created a website with HTML, CSS and PHP Created an application promoting accessibility using

Created guides using Oxygen XML and Heretto

#### Certifications

The Art of API documentation - Udemy Learn API Technical Writing JSON and XML for Writers - Udemy Designing accessible editorial content for the web - Access 42 Cloud Foundations - Scaleway Cloud Network - Scaleway

# **TOOLBOX**

Algolia ) ( Amplitude

Confluence

Markdown



(Slack)

(Snagit

VSCode

# **STRENGTHS**

## **Documentation Evangelist**

Building cross-team relationships, liaising with clients

#### **Tech Facilitator**

Simplifying complex topics, being a quick-learner, training team mates

#### **Decision Maker**

Anticipating user experience risks, balancing perfection with viability, choosing practical solutions

## **LANGUAGES**

English: Fluent French: Native German: Fluent Spanish: Advanced Arabic: Intermediate Chinese: Beginner

## **ABOUT ME**

I am a technical writer with more than 4 years of experience structuring and simplifying complex information to ensure optimal user experience. I specialize in different cloud solutions and I am looking for opportunities in tech companies that use the docs-as-code approach. I am based in Paris, but open to relocate.

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Technical Writer**

2021 - Now

Scaleway

#### As a documentation team representative in product squads, I:

- Write and review technical documentation for all of Scaleway's products and services, including how-tos, tutorials, FAQs, quickstarts, concepts, troubleshooting, and API reference
- Write UX copy for the Scaleway console
- Create interactive user guides (Guideflow) and short instructional videos to improve the discoverability and usability of the Scaleway console
- Create Amplitude dashboards and share insights with product teams
- Create new troubleshooting pages based on support feedback
- Participate in brainstorming sessions and in making decisions about the product

#### As a technical writer in the team, I:

- Lead retrospectives and team weeklies
- Built an internal onboarding website to centralize team processes for new team
- Co-organized and presented at the Documentation Team's external meetup
- Deliver onboarding sessions and cross-company talks about Technical Writing
- Update doc site metadata and structure to improve SEO visibility

## Service Civique (French voluntary community service)

2019 - 2020

Centre social Saint-Martin, France

- Taught English
- Adapted content to varied learning styles, proficiency levels, and interests

## **French Teaching Assistant**

2017-2018

Gesamtschule Emsland, Lingen, Germany

Taught French, conducted evaluations, and coordinated school activities

## **Tourism and Communication Intern**

2015-2016

Office de Tourisme et des Congrès du Saint-Quentinois, France

- Designed and published social media content to promote local attractions
- Handled customer requests in French, English, and German via phone and email
- Supported street marketing campaigns to promote events and improve visitor turnout